トロンコ そろそろ巡回は来るぞ
Tronco, it's about time for the cops to make their rounds.
本字幕由✿花語&千夏字幕組✿共同製作
Why don't we just grease their palms a little?
サツなんて ちょっと労いしときゃいいでしょう
Scusa's not satisfied with "a little."
スクーサ様はちょっとじゃ済まなかったな
Scusa?
スクーサ？
The new Federal Bureau of Prohibition head.
新任の連邦取締官だ
オルコ ファミリーの至高タマ貰ってるらしい
I hear he's taken a small fortune from the Orco family.
おい 大した運転だな
Hey, watch your driving!
I thought you'd been driving taxis up 'til now.
この間までタクシー 転がしてたんだろうがよ
All the booze in the back is throwing us off.
血に積みまくった酒で振られるんですよ
お陰で稼ぎが違うんだろうが
But it's putting more money in your pockets, isn't it?
Mr. Vanno, once I save up enough, I'm gonna buy a car.
ヴァンノさん 俺稼いだら車買うんです
A Phantom.
ファントム
Sure.
後百回酒運んだら 俺が買ってやるよ
A hundred more booze runs, and I'll buy one for you.
Really?! I'll hold you to that!
本当ですか 約束ですよ
まだ二人共生きてたらな
Assuming we're both still alive, that is.
来たぞ 急げ
It's them. Hurry!
隠れろ
Hide!
行ったね
They're gone.
おい トロンコ
Hey, Tronco.
We're safe now.
もう大丈夫だ
おい
Hey!
さっさと戻ろうぜ
Let's get back.
後一匹残ってるな
There's one left.
始末しろ
Put him down.
kanjou ni tsukeru
I can assign whatever name I wish
namae wa jiyuu dane
To these emotions
hora kawarihateta
See, they've already ceased to change.
kesenai boku no
The trigger of
tsumi no hikigane ga
My unerepentable sins
toketeshimaisou de
Seems ready to melt away,
nikushimi ga kieteshimattara
But if this hatefulness fades,
kimi o korosenai kara
I'll lose my chance to kill you
kako o tannou shiteiru
I'm experiencing every moment of my past,
tsumi ga tsukutta boku ni kawaru tame ni
Trying to become the person who created these sins
ASL no naifu de
With an ASL knife.
kioku no signal kizamareteru noni
Despite the signal carved into my memories,
itami sae keshisatteshimau kizuna no spiral
Even the pain is erased away by this spiral of causality
Having wandered in, I begin to fade... ceasing to be myself.
mayoikonda boku wa boku de kietekureteiku
Phantom of Falsehood
Daya 2
虛偽的幻影
オルコとはもう戦争するしなねぇ
I tell you, it's war against the Orcos now.
おい
Hey!
You clung to the underside of the truck to escape, huh?
トラックにしがみついて逃げ出すなんて
Pretty smart thinking, for you.
お前にしちゃ 上出来だ
Hey.
おぉ 遅かったな
Hey, you're late.
親父が喜ぶ
Dad's gonna love it.
いや お祝いだ
No, it's a gift for the party.
Drink it.
飲んでくれ
あれと比べると 大分見劣りするけどな
Though I realize it hardly compares to that...
ファントム
A Phantom?
It's from the Galassias.
ガラシアからだ
Galassias?
ガラシア?
やっぱいけてんな
That's good stuff!
花婿はシカゴを牛耳るドン ガラシアの甥だ
The groom is the nephew of Don Galassia,
the guy who controls Chicago.
この町はヴァッティが仕切ってんだ
The Vanettis own this town.
ガラシアの手助けなんていらねぇ
We don't need the Galassias' help.
Funny, I heard you lost some turf downtown to the Orco family.
ダウンタウンの島は
オルコファミリに取られたって聞いたけど
言葉には気を付けろ
You'd better watch your mouth!
ネロ
Nero.
親父さんが呼んでいる
Your father is calling you.
あぁ
Sure.
バルベロ
Barbero.
俺のここだ
The brains of my operation.
アヴィリオにコルテオ
Avilio and Corteo.
よろしく 話は聞いてる
A pleasure. I've heard all about you.
じゃ 楽しんでいってくれ
Well, have fun.
どういうこ
What are you thinking?
We came here because we needed the money!
お金が必要だからってここに来たのに
こんなところ 早く出よう
We need to get out of here.
せっかく来たんだ 楽しめよ
It's a party. Let's enjoy ourselves.
劇場の方はどうだ
How's the playhouse coming along?
順調だ
It's all going smoothly.
Should be done by the end of June.
六月いっぱいには完成する
Big Brother, Don Galassia's decided to come to the big opening.
兄さん 杮落としには
ドン ガラシアも来ることになったよ
後三ヶ月だ
We've got three months.
Then Vanetti, Orco, and Galassia...
そこで ヴァッティ オルコ ガラシア
三つのファミリーが一度に会することになる
All three families will be in the same place.
それでどうなる
So what?
確かに最近のオルコに目に余る
I know the Orcos have been overstepping lately,
but they have to do as the Galassias say, too.
だけど 奴らはガラシアの言葉には
従わなきゃならない
So do we.
俺達ヴァッティもだろう
俺はもう長くない
I don't have much time left.
But I intend to leave the family on solid footing.
だがなぁ ファミリーの土台だけは
しっかりさせておくつもりだ
だから姉さんはガラシアの甥と結婚した
That's why Sis is marrying Galassia's nephew.
ロナルドはいいやつだし 信用出来る
Ronaldo's a good guy. We can trust him.
ほぼなにも問題...
Nothing left to worry—
They killed another of ours.
また一人やられた
オルコの酒を取ったからだろ
That's because we stole Orco's booze.
あのルートも三ヶ月前まではうちのもんだった
That route was ours until three months ago.
てめえの島も守れねぇファミリーに先はねぞ
A family that can't protect their own turf has no future.
一本どうだ
Care for a cigar?
葉巻ってやつだが 煙を吸うんじゃない
With a cigar, you don't inhale smoke.
時間を吸うんだ
You inhale time.
よく考えろう
Think carefully,
そしてゆっくりと歩め
then walk forward with purpose.
速く走ろうとするものほど転びやすいものだ
The faster you rush out, the more likely you are to trip and fall.
自ら動かぬものに天は
その手を差し伸べずとも言うぜ
There's another saying: "God helps those who help themselves."
あのやろう
That piece of shit.
フィオを泣かせやがったら 俺がぶっ殺してやる
If he makes Fio cry, I'll beat the crap out of him.
ご機嫌斜めだな
I see you're in a foul mood.
ロナルド様の御なりった
I think Master Ronaldo is paying us a call.
おめでどう
Congratulations.
晴れて私も君たちのファミリーというわけだ
I'm now officially a member of your family.
ネロは?
Where's Nero?
Don Vanetti requested his presence.
ドン ヴァネッティとちょっとな
娘の結婚式にも顔を出さないで 閉じこもってる
He's locked up in his room, and won't even come to his own daughter's wedding?
用心深さもすぎれば臆病
Too much caution just becomes cowardice.
表には伏せているんだな
We're keeping this within the family,
but he's staying indoors on his doctor's recommendation.
外に出るのは医者から控えるようにと
まぁ オルコとのことは私がどうにかする
Well, I'll fix your little Orco problem for you.
大体こんなしけた町で
ちまちま争っている意味が分からないね
Not that I get the point of fighting over this backwater burg.
たかが国境からきた酒を運ぶ通り道だろう
It's just a pit stop on the way of hauling booze over the border.
よせ
Don't.
滑稽だな
That's funny.
何がだ
What is?
トラの威を借るキツネは滑稽だと言っている
Watching an ass strut around in a lion's skin.
てめえいったい誰の...
Who the hell do you think—
そこまでだ
Stop it, now!
What's wrong?
どうしたの
いつまでも子供ね
You'll never grow up, will you?
お似合いだぜ
They're a perfect couple.
下戸は辛いな
Teetotalers have it rough.
どうだい
What do you think?
これが例の酒か
This is the liquor you mentioned?
凄いキックだな
It's got quite a kick.
Where do you make it?
どこで作ってる?
キッチン アパートの
The kitchen... in my apartment.
だろう
Right?
I haven't seen that look on your face in ages!
お前のそんな顔久しぶりだぜ
Can we talk in private?
ちょっと話せるか
虎の威を借る狐か
An ass in a lion's skin, huh?
口も達者なんだな
You have a way with words.
改めてになるが
I don't think we've been introduced.
ヴァンノ クレメンテだ
Vanno Clemente.
アヴィリオ ブルノ
Avilio Bruno.
あんたとは上手くやっていけそうだ
I think we'll make a good team.
味わって食え
Enjoy it.
ヴァンノ様特製 ローレス風チョッピーノだ
This is Maestro Vanno's special Lawless-style cioppino.
旨そうだ
Looks great!
おい
Hey!
父よ あなたの慈しみに
感謝してこの食事を頂きます
Father in Heaven, we thank you for the meal in which we now partake.
私達の心と体を支える糧としてください
We pray that it might nourish our bodies and our souls.
くそ
Damn it!
まだ痛むのか
Does it still hurt?
しばらくは飯抜きで
I won't be eating for a while.
そういや あのアヴィリオってやつ おもしれいな
That reminds me. That Avilio guy's pretty interesting, huh?
一緒にいたコルテオってやつの酒も 相当いける
And that Corteo fellow who was with him makes a mean brew.
オルコと無駄にやり合わなくて済むな
Yeah. Maybe we won't have to press things with the Orcos.
それについじゃ ドンと話したんだろう
You talked to the don about that, right?
おい ネロ ファンゴはやるんだろうな?
Hey, Nero. We're taking out Fango, aren't we?
いや
No.
なんで
Why not?!
Galassia wants the Vanettis and the Orcos to make nice.
ガラシアは俺達ヴァッティと
オルコの手打ちをご所望だ
ふざけるな
That's bullshit!
How's Tronco supposed to rest in peace, then?
このままじゃ トロンコは浮かばれね
I'll do it myself if I have to!
俺一人でもやる
酔ってんのか ヴァンノ
Are you drunk, Vanno?
オルコには勝てても ガラシアとは...
Even if you could beat the Orcos, the Galassias...
やってもみねで 勝つも負けるもあるがよ
We won't know if we don't even try!
We need funds first. If we had that booze—
まずは資金だ あの酒さえあ...
Okay, we'll kill him.
よし やるか
ただし...
But...
引き金を引くのは俺達じゃねがな
We won't be the ones pulling the trigger.
やるよ
I'll do it.
本気なの?
You mean it?
If I take out Fango, I can join the family, right?
ファンゴをやれば ファミリに入れるんだな
話持って来といたなんだが
I know I'm the one who brought it up,
こいつは危ねぇ仕事だ
but this is a dangerous job.
They recently killed one of our young guys.
この間も若いのが殺された
Let me try.
やらせてくれ
水曜の夜
Wednesday night.
He'll be spending some time at Lacrima's house.
奴は必ずラクリマの家で過ごす
Lacrima?
ラクリマ?
ファンゴの愛人だ
Fango's mistress.
ローレスクロニクルの
向かえのアパートに住んでる
Her apartment's across from the Lawless Chronicle.
そういつはどうする
What should I do about her?
一緒にやっちまえばいい
Eh, you can kill her, too.
これまでに殺しは
Ever killed before?
いや
No.
そうか
I see.
Well, you're getting a late start, then.
まぁ お前の年じゃ遅いくらいだ
おれん時は...
My first was...
また連絡する
I'll be in touch later.
あんな奴らと一緒になって正気じゃないよ
You're joining up with guys like him? That's insane!
Yeah.
なにもかも狂ってしまった
The whole world's gone mad.
親父の親友ってのは
They claim to be my dad's best friend,
復讐に協力したいそうだ
and want to help me with my revenge.
奇妙な話だろう
Bizarre, isn't it?
ご丁寧に 大切な物を奪った奴らの名前まで
I'm handed everything,
even the names of the men who stole the people I loved...
残り半分は上手く行ってからだ
You'll get the other half after you succeed.
Oh, sure.
あぁ うん
大丈夫 何も問題はない
Don't worry. It'll be fine.
おぃ
Hey!
くっせ ったく どんだけ飲んでんだ
You stink. Just how soused are you?
おい ここで寝んな
Hey! You can't sleep here!
友達が住んでるんだ
My friend lives here.
知るかよ
You think I care?
ほら ささっと失せろ
Go on, get lost!
セルペンテさん
Mr. Serpente!
丁度いいや
Perfect timing.
What is it?
なにか
家ね 上等なのが入ったんですよ
I got some good stuff in here.
ここじゃ目に付くんで 車の中で
We're too conspicuous here. Let's go to the car.
あぁ そうだ 力を込めろ
That's right. Harder!
もっと もっとだ
Harder! Harder, damn it!
休んでないで さっさと来いよ
Don't stop. Keep it coming!
とんだ豚ね
You filthy pig.
豚 豚
Pig! Pig!
ドア開ける前にはノックしろってママに
教わらなかったのか ボイー
Didn't your mama ever teach you to knock, little boy?!
Please... Don't do it!
ちょっと やめてよ
いいぜ
I like it.
I'm getting chills all over.
たまんなぇ ぞくぞくする
楽しくなってきた てめぇも一緒にやるか
This is getting fun! You wanna join in?
Go on! Fire!
ほら 来い 打ってみろ
Don't fire... Please...
やめて 撃たないで お願い
早く撃ち込んで来いよ
Come on, shoot one off already...
Fire that bad boy real good...
大事なあれでよ
お前は...
You're...
ファンゴは
Where's Fango?
逃がしちまったか
He got away, huh?
Yeah.
すまない
Sorry.
相手が相手だ
We knew he was a tough one.
It's not your fault.
しかたねぇ
此奴か
It's him...
ヴァネッティのあんたがオルコの人間を
やるのはまずいんじゃないのか
Won't it make trouble if a Vanetti like you kills an Orco?
オールドビレッジの墓行く
We'll go to the graveyard in the old village.
サツだ 先に行っててくれ
It's the cops. I'll meet you there.
われ 主の限りなく嫌い給う罪を持って
O my God, I am heartily sorry for having offended thee,
這是天主教的「痛悔經」,直接copy經文的文言翻譯了,
為了順應字幕長度,不會與日譯語序對照...
限りなく愛すべき御父に背きしを深く悔み奉る
and I detest all my sins because of thy just punishments,
御子イエズス キリストの
流し給える御血の功徳によりて
but most of all because they offend thee, my God,
わが罪を赦し給え
who art all good and deserving of all my love.
聖寵の助けをもって今より心を改め
I firmly resolve, with the help of thy grace,
再び罪を犯して 御心に
背くことあるまじと決心し奉る
to sin no more and avoid the near occasions of sin.
アーメン
Amen.
この下にトロンコが眠ってる
This is where we laid Tronco to rest.
気のいいやつだなぁ
He was a good guy.
He liked cars.
車がすきだった
あぁ クソ
Damn it...
セルペンテ 祈れ
Serpente. Start praying.
頼む
Please...
死にたくねぇよ お願いだ
I don't want to die! Please!
何も誰もやらねぇ
I won't kill anyone ever again.
I'll cut ties with Orco and Fango.
オルコ ファンゴとも縁を切る
トロンコの前で殺すのか?
You're going to kill me in front of Tronco?
You'll stain his grave with blood?
墓を血で汚すのか?
Not gonna pray?
祈らないのか?
Don't do this! I don't want to die!
嫌だよ 死にたくねぇよ
そうか
I see.
嫌だ
No!
ったく 罰当たりの野郎だ
May God have mercy on your soul.
あの夜
That night...
俺の家族をやったのは
The ones who killed my family were
ヴィンセントヴァネッティ
Vincente Vanetti,
息子のNero
his son Nero...
そして
And...
ヴァンノ クレメンテ
Vanno Clemente.
お前は...
Who are... you?
俺の名はアンジェロ
My name is Angelo.
I'm the son of a man you killed...
お前らに殺された
テスタ ラグーザの息子だ
The son of Testa Lagusa.
落ち着け
Calm down!
此奴の言い分を聞いてからだ
Let's hear his side of it first.
ヴァンノが銃を奪われて
He stole Vanno's gun.
俺がセルペンテを撃ったが 遅かった
I shot Serpente, but it was too late.
縄を掛けなかったのか?
Your hands weren't tied?
Serpente said he'd let me pray.
祈らせてくれっとセルペンテが
それでヴァンノが縄を
Then he tied up Vanno...
連れて行け
Take me there.
その場所に
To where it happened.
あそこで
Over there...
二人が...
That's where they...